Guide to the Guantánamo Bay Detention Camp Collection: Seton Hall University Law School Center for Policy and Research Records TAM.472
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Guantanámo Bay Detention Camp Collection: Seton Hall University Law School Center for Policy and Research Records
2002-ongoing
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Denbeaux, Mark P.
Seton Hall University. School of Law. Center for Policy & Research
TAM.472
0.5 Linear Feet in one manuscript box.
4 websites in 4 archived websites.
Guantanámo Bay Detention Camp Collection: Seton Hall University Law School Center for Policy and Research Records (2002-ongoing) is part of a joint project involving Seton Hall University Law School's Center for Policy and Research and the Tamiment Library to document the legal and public policy issues related to the administration of the Guantánamo Bay Detention Facility by the United States Department of Defense. The Center for Policy and Research was established in 2006 by Mark P. Denbeaux to analyze government data to illuminate the interrogations and intelligence practices of the United States.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Mark Denbeaux on behalf of Seton Hall University's Center for Policy and Research; additional materials were donated in 2010. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 2009.014, 2010.069, and 2010.078.
http://law.shu.edu/ProgramsCenters/PublicIntGovServ/policyresearch/Guantanamo-Reports.cfm and linked PDFs were initially selected by curators and captured through the use of The California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service in 2009 as part of the Guantánamo Bay Detention Camp & War Crimes (U.S.) Web Archive. In 2015, the URL redirected to https://law.shu.edu/policy-research/guantanamo-reports.cfm and was added to the collection. In November 2015, these websites were migrated to Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In November 2024, https://law.shu.edu/center-policy-research/guantanamo-reports.html was added. The accession number associated with this website is 2025.003.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two series:
Series I: Guantánamo Reports, 2006-2009
Series II: Death in Camp Delta Files, 2002-2010
Series I is arranged chronologically and Series II is arranged alphabetically.
Historical Note
Etablished in 2006, Seton Hall University School of Law's Center for Policy and Research is led by Professor Mark P. Denbeaux and focuses on the issues of "Interrogations & Intelligence, National Security, and Forensics." Denbeaux's work for Guantánamo Bay detainees led him to lead the production of a series of reports on Guantánamo that have become the Center's most well-known initiative. Fellows with the Center for Policy and Research analyze government data to illuminate the interrogations and intelligence practices of the United States. The reports have been introduced into the Congressional record by the Senate Armed Services Committee, the Senate Judiciary Committee, the House Armed Services Committee, and as part of a resolution by the European Parliament.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Guantánamo Bay Detention Camp Collection: Dorsey and Whitney, LLP Records (TAM 509)
Scope and Content Note
Guantanámo Bay Detention Camp Collection: Seton Hall University Law School Center for Policy and Research Records (2002-ongoing) is part of a joint project involving Seton Hall University Law School's Center for Policy and Research and the Tamiment Library to document the legal and public policy issues related to the administration of the Guantánamo Bay Detention Facility by the United States Department of Defense. The majority of the collection is made up of reports written by Mark Denbeaux and other fellows on the United States intelligence and interrogations practices at Guantánamo Bay Dentention Camp and Camp Delta.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted. Born-digital materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies. To request that material be transferred, or if you are unsure if material has been transferred, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
Accruals
Additional materials will be added to the collection over time.
Conditions Governing Access
Series I is open to researchers without restrictions. Series II is restricted.
Take Down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.
If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.
If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.
Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Iraq War, 2003-2011 -- Prisoners and prisons, American.; Habeas corpus -- United States; Iraq War, 2003-2011 -- Moral and ethical aspects -- United States.; Afghan War, 2001-; Terrorism.; War on Terrorism, 2001-2009 -- Moral and ethical aspects; War on Terrorism, 2001-2009.; Torture -- United States; Seton Hall University. School of Law. Center for Policy & Research; Denbeaux, Mark P.; Denbeaux, Mark P.; al Zahrani, Yasser Talal, 1984-2006; Ahmed, Ali Abdullah, 1970-2006; Al-Utaybi, Mani Shaman Turki al-Habardi, 1981-2006; United States. Joint Task Force Guantánamo; Denbeaux & Denbeaux; Dickstein Shapiro; Guantánamo Bay Detention Camp; Davis, Jeffrey J.
- Series I: Guantánamo Reports, 2006-ongoing
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains paper and PDFs captured in the web archives of the reports on Guantánamo published by the Center for Policy and Research. These reports have examined Guantánamo through analyzing Department of Defense data.
  Accruals
  Archived websites are captured semiannually.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically by publication date.
  - "Report on Guantánamo Detainees: A Profile of 517 Detainees through Analysis of Department of Defense Data", February 8, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Second Report on the Guantánamo Detainees: Inter- and Intra-Departmental Disagreements about Who is Our Enemy", March 20, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Guantánamo Detainees during Detention: Data from Department of Defense Records", July 10, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "June 10th Suicides at Guantánamo: Government Words and Deeds Compared", August 21, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "No-Hearing Hearings: CSRT: The Modern Habeas Corpus?", [November 17, 2006] (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "The 14 Myths of Guantánamo" (Mark P. Denbeaux testimony before Senate Armed Services Committee), [April 26, 2007] (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "The Empty Battlefield and the Thirteenth Criterion", [Nov 8, 2007?] (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "The Meaning of 'Battlefield:' An Analysis of the Government's Representations of 'Battlefield' Capture and 'Recidivism' of the Guantánamo Detainees", [December 10, 2007] (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Capture on Tape: Interrogation and Videotaping of Detainees in Guantánamo", [Febuary 7, 2008] (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Released Guantánamo Detainees and the Department of Defense: Propaganda by the Numbers?", [Jan 15, 2009] (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Archived Websites, July 2009-ongoing